the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license
以下内容是根据Creative Commons授权提供
your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
您的支持将有助于麻省理工学院开放式课程继续报价
high-quality educational resources for free
免费优质教育资源
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of them IT
进行捐赠或查看附加材料由数百人资讯
courses
课程
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at 0 CW
参观麻省理工学院开放式课程在0 CW
that MIT ided you
麻省理工学院被提供的你
home
家
in
the No
否
for in the last lecture
在上一讲
I introduced an illustrated the kinds of signals and systems that will be dealing
我介绍一本图文并茂的各种信号和系统，将处理
with
同
throughout this course in today's lecture I'd like to
整个过程在今天的演讲中，我想
be a little more specific and in particular talk about
是一个更具体一点，尤其是说说
some the basic signals both continuous-time and discrete-time
一些基本的信号都连续时间和离散时间
that will form important building blocks as
这将形成重要的组成部分为
the course progresses let's begin
课程的进展，让我们开始
with one signal the continuous-time sinusoidal signal which perhaps you're
同一个信号的连续时间正弦信号，也许你
already
已经
somewhat familiar with mathematically
稍微熟悉数学
the continuous-time sinusoidal signal is expressed as i've indicated here
连续时间正弦信号表示为我在这里表示
there are three parameters
有三个参数
a Omega 0 and see the parameter a is referred to as
一个欧米茄0，看到了一个参数被称为
the ample to the parameter Omega 0
充足的参数欧米茄0
as the frequency and the parameter fee
随着频率和参数费
as the face and
作为脸和
graphically the continuous-time sinusoidal signal has the form
图形的连续时间正弦信号的形式
shown here now
现在这里显示
the sinusoidal signal has a number love
的正弦信号具有许多爱
important properties that will find it convenient to exploit as the
这将是很方便的利用作为重要性质
course goes along one of which is
当然随之而来的是一
the fact that the sinusoidal signal
一个事实，即正弦信号
is what is referred to as periodic what I mean by periodic
是什么是周期性称为周期性我是什么意思
is that under inappropriate time shift which I indicate here
是，在不合适的时间偏移，我在此说明
as t0 the signal replicates
作为T0信号重复
or repeats itself force it another way
或重演强迫它的另一种方式
if we shift the time origin by an appropriate amount
如果我们用一个适当的量移位的时间原点
t0 the smallest value t0 being referred to as the period
T0最小的值T0被称为周期
then X 50 is equal to itself shifted and
然后X 50等于它本身转移及
to demonstrate that we can demonstrated mathematically
证明我们可以用数学证明
by simply substituting into the mathematical expression for the
通过简单的代入的数学表达式
sinusoidal signal
正弦信号
see plus capital T zero
见加上大写字母T为零
in place if T when we carry out the expansion
在地方，如果T当我们进行扩展
we then have for the argument the sinusoid
我们再对参数的正弦曲线
Omega 0t plus Omega 0
Omega欧米茄加0T 0
capital T zero plus P now
现在大写字母T零加p
one of the things that we know about sinusoidal functions
那我们知道正弦函数的一件事
is dead if you change the argument by any integer multiple
如果您通过任何整数倍改变参数是死的
to pie and the function has the same value
以饼和函数具有相同的值
and so we can exploit that here in particular
所以我们可以在这里特别利用
with Omega 0t0 and integer multiple
欧米茄0T0和整数倍
up to par i then the right hand side of this equation
达到标准这个方程i，那么在右手侧
is equal to the left hand side of the equation so
等于等式的左手侧，从而
with Omega 0t0 equal to two part times an integer
欧米茄0T0等于两个部分时间的整数
or t0 equal to two part times an integer
或T0等于2倍的部分的一个整数
divided by Omega 0 the signal repeats the period is defined as the smallest
由欧米茄0除以信号重复周期被定义为最小的
value if t0 and so the period is to pie
如果T0值，所以周期是馅饼
divided by Omega 0 and going back to
由欧米茄0分，并要回
are sinusoidal signal we can
是正弦信号，我们可以
see that and
看到这一点，
i've indicated here then the period
我在这里表示那么这个期限
as to pie over Omega 0 and that's the bad you
以饼图在欧米茄0，这就是你不好
under which the signal repeats now
根据该信号现在重复
in addition a useful
另外一个有用的
property above the sinusoidal signal is the fact that
属性的正弦信号以上的事实是
a timeshare all a sinusoid
分时所有的正弦曲线
is equivalent to a phase change and we can demonstrate
相当于一个相位变化，我们能够证明
that again mathematically in particular
一遍数学特别
if we put the sinusoidal signal under
如果我们把正弦信号下
a timeshare i've indicated that the probe the time shift that i'm talking
分时我已经指出，探针时的转变，我说的
about. by small t0
约。小T0
and expand this out then
并扩大了这一点，然后
we see that that is equivalent to
我们看到，它等效于
a change in phase and important thing to recognize
在第二阶段，并认识到重要的一点变化
about this statement is that not only is a timeshare
关于本声明的是，不仅是分时度假
generating a phase change but in fact
产生的相位变化，但是实际上
if we inserted a phase change
如果我们插入了一个相变
there is always a value if t0
总有一个值，如果T0
which would correspond to
这将对应于
an equivalent I'm ship said another way
等效的，我的船说另一种方式
if retake Omega 0t0
如果再拿欧米茄0T0
and think of that as are change in phase
并认为那是有变化的相
for any change in phase we can solve this equation for timeshift
在阶段的任何变化，我们可以解决这个方程时光平移
or conversely for any value timeshare that
或者相反，对于任何价值的分时度假
represents an appropriate face
代表适量涂于面部
so a time shift corresponds to a phase change
这样一个时间移位对应于相变
and a phase change likewise corresponds to it I'm ship
和一种相变同样对应于它我船
and so for example if we
因此，例如，如果我们
look at the sinusoidal signal
看看正弦信号
the general sinusoidal signal that we
一般的正弦信号，我们
saw previously in effect changing the phase
实际上之前看到的改变相
corresponds to moving this signal in time
对应于时间提出这个信号
one way or the other for example if we look at the sinusoidal signal with
一种方式或其他，例如，如果我们看一下正弦信号
a phase equal to 0 that corresponds
一个相位等于0，其对应
to locating the time origin at this p
到定位时间原点在这个P
and i've indicated that on
我已经表明，在
the following grass
下面的草
so here we have illustrated a sinusoid
所以在这里，我们已经说明了正弦曲线
with zero phase or cosine with zero phase
零相位或余弦零相位
corresponding to taking a general picture and shifting it
相应采取概貌和它转移
shifting it appropriately as i've indicated here
它适当地转移，因为我已经在这里表示
this of course still has the property that it's a periodic function
这当然还是有，这是一个周期函数的性质
since we simply displaced in time
因为我们只是在时间上移位
and by looking at the graph what we see is that it has another very important
并且通过观察该图我们看到的是，它有另外一个非常重要
property
属性
a property referred to as even and
一个属性称为均匀
that's a property that will find it useful in general
这是一个属性，会发现它在一般有用
to refer to in relation to signals a signal is said to be even
参考有关的信号的信号被认为是什
if when we reflected about the origin it looks exactly the same so it's a metric
如果当我们反映关于原点它看起来完全一样的，所以它是一个度量
about the origin and looking at
关于起源和看
this sinusoid that in fact has that property
此正弦波，其实有一个属性
and mathematically this statement that it's even is equivalent to the statement
和数学这条语句，它甚至相当于声明
that if we replace the time argument
如果我们更换时间参数
by its negative the function itself
其负函数本身
doesn't change
不改变
now this corresponded to a phase shift 0 in our original
现在这相当于在我们原来的相移0
cosine expression if instead we had
余弦表达式，如果不是我们有
chosen a phase shift love let's say minus pie over to
选择了一个相移的爱，让我们说减派过来
then is that a a cosigner so it'll signal
然后是一个一个联署所以它会发出信号
well we would generate is a sinusoid
好，我们会产生一个正弦
with the appropriate phase or
用适当的相位或
said another way if we take are
换个说法，如果我们采取有
original cosine and
原来余弦和
substitute in for the phase minus pie over to
在替换为相减派过来
then of course we have this mathematical expression
那么当然我们有这个数学表达式
using just straight for trigonometric identities
只使用直三角恒等式
we can express that alternately as signed Omega 0t
我们可以交替表达，作为签署欧米茄0吨
the frequency and amplitude of course haven't changed and
当然，频率和幅度没有改变，并
that you can convince yourself also is equivalent
你可以说服自己也就相当于
to shifting the cosine by
以通过移动余弦
and a mountain time that I've indicated here namely
而且我在这里表示，即山时间
a quarter of the period so illustrated below
一季度期间所以如下图所示
is the graph now when
是图现在时
we have a phase of mine espy over to an arc cosine
我们有我的一个阶段窥探了一个反余弦
which is a sinusoidal signal of course it's still
这当然是一个正弦波信号，它仍然
periodic its periodic with a period of two pi
定期的周期性，周期为2 PI
over Omega 0 again because all that we've done
在欧米茄0再次因为所有我们所做的
by introducing a phase change is
通过引入相变是
introduce the timeshare now
现在介绍分时度假
when we look at the sinusoid in comparison with the Cosi namely with
当我们看正弦曲线与COSI比较，即与
this particular choice a phase
这个特殊的选择相
this has a different symmetry and
此具有不同的对称性和
that symmetry is referred to as odd what ought symmetry means
该对称被称为奇数什么应该对称手段
graphically is that when we flipped the signal
图形化的是，当我们翻转的信号
about the origin
关于原点
but I margin we also multiply it by a minus sign
但我利润率，我们也通过一个减号乘以
so thats in effect antisymmetric
实际上反对称因此多数民众赞成
it it's not the mirror image but it's the mirror image flipped over
但它不是镜像，但它的镜像翻转
and will find many occasions not only to refer to signals more general and
并会发现许多场合，不仅指信号更一般和
sinusoidal signals as
正弦信号作为
even in some cases and odd in other cases
甚至在某些情况下，奇在其他情况下
and in general mathematically
和一般的数学
on signal is one which
上信号是其中之一
has satisfy is the algebraic expression
有满足的是代数式
that exit see when you replace
该出口看，当你更换
TE by its negative is equal to
TE通过其负面等于
minus exit -2 so replacing the argument by its negative
减去出口-2获其负面替换参数
corresponds to time River I A
对应于时间河I A
an algebraic sign rivers
一个代数符号河流
okay so in this is the class of continuous-time
行，以便在这个类的连续时间
sinusoids will have a little more to say about it later
血窦将有更多一点后来说一下吧
but I've now like to turn to
但我现在想谈谈
discrete-time sinusoids what we'll see is that discrete-time sinusoids
离散时间血窦就是我们要看到的是，离散时间正弦信号
are very much like continuous-time ones but also
非常像连续时间的，但也
with some very important differences and we want to focus not only on the
有一些非常重要的区别，我们希望不仅着眼于
similarities
相似之处
but also on the differences well let's begin
同时也对差异以及让我们开始吧
with the mathematical expression a
用数学表达式
discrete-time sinusoidal signal mathematically
离散时间正弦信号在数学上
is as i've indicated here a cosine
是因为我在这里表示一个余弦
Omega 0 and plus the and just says
欧米茄0加，只是说：
in the continuous-time case the parameter
在连续时间的情况下的参数
a is what we refer to as the airport to
一个就是我们所说的机场
Omega 0 as the frequency and see
ω-0的频率和看
as the face
作为脸
and I've illustrated
我已经说明
here several discrete-time
这里几个离散时间
sinusoidal signals and they kinda
正弦信号，他们还挺
look similar in fact if you sort of track what you might think of is the
看起来其实相类似的，如果你跟踪你可能会想到的是什么
envelope
信封
it looks very much like what a continuous-time sign outside so it might
它看起来非常像一个连续时间签署外，这样它可能
look like
像
but keep in mind day at the independent variable in this case
但要记住每天在这种情况下，自变量
isn't integer variable and so
是不是整型变量等
the sequence in fact only takes on bag use
其实序列只对包的使用
at integer values up the argument and we'll see
在整数值起来的说法，我们会看到
that that has a a very important
即，有一个很重要的
implication and will see that shortly now
言下之意，并会看到，现在很快
one of the issues that we addressed in the continuous-time cases periodicity
那我们在连续时间情况下，周期性解决的问题之一
and I want to refer or return to that
我想引用或返回到
shortly because that is in fact one of the areas where there is an important
不久，因为这是事实的地方有一个重要的